let's look at the solution to a raid for
quiz we have a rate for array with five
discs and one disc has 200 gigabytes in
capacity the data capacity of the array
is the data capacity of all but one
discs because we sacrifice a single disk
to parity so among the five discs one is
parity the other ones contain data so we
have four times this much which is eight
hundred gigabytes the throughput of the
array for reads is going to be the
throughput of the four data discs so we
have forty megabytes per second
throughput for reads but for rights is
going to be half a true put of a single
disc and that's because the parity disk
needs to be both read and written for
every right so we get five megabytes per
second here so now we need to figure out
what happens during one second well this
throughput is eight times the throughput
of the rights which means in every given
second one ninth of a second will be
spent on reeds and eighth ninth of a
second will be spent on rights that way
we spend eight times as much time on
rights as we do for raids which allows
us to do the same number of reads and
writes so now the overall throughput
will be what we can read in one ninth of
a second plus what we can write in
eighth ninth of a second and that ends
up being 80 over nine megabytes so this
is what we can do in a second so our
average throughput ends up being eight
point eighty nine megabytes per second
again just like in a raid one quiz we
cannot simply average the throughput for
reads and the throughput for rights we
would get something more than 20
megabytes a second if we do that but
that would do a lot more reads than
rights because it assumes that half a
second we are reading and we managed to
read 20 megabytes and then half a second
we are writing and managed to write 2.5
five megabytes as you can see the read
to write ratio is not fifty-fifty here
so that is again why we get this and not
just the simple average of these tool so
the final question here is what's the
MTTF we know that the MTTF of rate for
is equal to the MTTF of one disk squared
divided by n times n minus 1 times the
time it takes us to replace a disk our n
in this case is 5 so we get five times
four times this and in this expression
again this is the time that we get to
work with the full rate for array until
we have a failed disk and this is how
many times we survive the repair without
the second disk failing the overall
number is 20 million 833 333 point 33
hours which again is much better than
this and we already said that this is
about 11 to 12 years this is more than
2,000 years remember that our raid 1 had
20,000 years so this is significantly
worse than raid 1 but on the other hand
we are working with five disks here and
spending only one-fifth of our capacity
on parity with raid 1 we were working
with only two disks and spending half of
the capacity of the array on parity so
we sacrifice some entity F to get better
cost per gigabyte but we still achieve a
very very high MTTF